Meet the women you don't know, behind the mission you do.
Hidden Figures is a drama, history film directed by Theodore Melfi.
The untold story of Katherine G.
Johnson, Dorothy Vaughan and Mary Jackson – brilliant African-American women working at NASA and serving as the
brains behind one of the greatest operations in history – the launch of astronaut John Glenn into orbit.
The visionary trio crossed all gender and race lines
to inspire generations to dream big.
Katherine G. Johnson, played by Taraji P. Henson.
Dorothy Vaughan, played by Octavia Spencer.
Mary Jackson, played by Janelle Monáe.
Al Harrison, played by Kevin Costner.
Vivian Mitchell, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Paul Stafford, played by Jim Parsons.
Hidden Figures is a 2016 American biographical drama film co-produced and directed by
Theodore Melfi, who co-wrote the screenplay with Allison Schroeder.
It is loosely based on the 2016 book by Margot Lee Shetterly.
It follows three female African-American
mathematicians, Katherine Goble Johnson (Taraji P.
Henson), Dorothy Vaughan (Octavia Spencer), and Mary Jackson (Janelle Monáe),
who worked at NASA during the Space Race in the 1950s and 1960s.
Other stars include Kevin Costner, Kirsten Dunst, Jim Parsons,
Mahershala Ali, Aldis Hodge, and Glen Powell.
Principal photography began in March 2016 in Atlanta,
Georgia, and wrapped up in May 2016.
Other filming locations included several other locations in Georgia,
including East Point, Canton, Monroe, Columbus, and Madison.
Hidden Figures had a limited release on December 25, 2016, by 20th
Century Fox, before going wide in on January 6, 2017.
The film received positive reviews, with praise for the performances (particularly Henson, Spencer and Monáe), the writing, direction,
cinematography, emotional tone, and historical accuracy, although some argued it featured a white savior narrative.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $236 million
worldwide against its $25 million production budget.
Deadline Hollywood noted it as one of the most profitable releases of 2016,
and estimated that it made a net profit of $95.5 million.
The film was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the top ten films of 2016 and received various awards
and nominations, including three nominations at the 89th Academy Awards, including Best Picture.
It also won the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding
Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture.
The film explores themes of nasa, mathematics,
sexism, biography, racial segregation.
The tone is emotional.